SHUBHAM PANDEY

+91 8269222551| spandev@tcd.ie | https://www.linkedin.com/in/shubham7117/ | Pune, India

PROFILE

As a dedicated and results-driven AI professional, I bring over **7 years** of diverse experience, working on multiple projects in **multiple countries**. With a **Master's degree in Artificial Intelligence from Trinity College Dublin, Ireland,** I have consistently demonstrated the ability to lead successful AI initiatives and collaborate effectively in team environments. My expertise spans a wide spectrum of AI domains, including **Generative AI**, **Deep Learning**, **Computer Vision**, **Machine Learning**, **AR/VR**, **and Software Development**. I have demonstrated a consistent track record of rapidly translating conceptual ideas into initial **Proof of Concepts (POCs)** and efficiently progressing to the development of **Minimum Viable Products (MVPs)** and ultimately, fully functional production-level AI applications.

SKILLS

Soft Skills: Project Management, Leadership, Problem Solving, Team Building, Presentation and Communication.

Languages: Python, C# (Unity3D), JS(React Js), Java.

Al: Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Deep learning, NLP, LLM.

AR/VR: Marker-based AR, Marker-less AR, SLAM, Feature Detection, AR Kit, Vuforia, Mobile and Web Based AR.

Framework: OpenCV, Langchain, Tensorflow (python, Js, TFLite), Scikit-Learn, OpenCV, NumPy, Keras, Pandas etc.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HEAD OF AI, AGILIS AS, OSLO, NORWAY

2021 - PRESENT

As the Head of Artificial Intelligence at Agilis AS, a prominent service-based company in Norway, I am **leading and managing the Research and Development (R&D) center for advanced AI development in India**. In this role, I oversee the development of cutting-edge AI solutions, my main responsibilities includes:

- Oversee project planning, execution and delivery, ensuring that projects are completed on time with high quality.
- Utilized agile and scrum methodologies to keep projects on track and ensure continuous improvement.
- Performing client interaction, quality check, code reviews, requirement analysis and feasibility analysis.
- Presenting AI initiatives and results to executive leadership and board members.
- **Designed and implemented robust AI software architectures** for complex projects, ensuring scalability, maintainability, and high performance.
- Orchestrated **full-cycle AI/ML development, custom-tailored to meet client specifications**, encompassing the entire journey from conceptualization to production.
- Proficient in deploying AI solutions across different platforms including **mobile apps and web applications**, facilitating real-time processing.
- Development of CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins and Bitbucket resulted in fast development, QA and deployment.
- Mentored and coached team members, fostering a culture of continuous learning and professional development.
- Continuously evaluated emerging AI architectural trends and integrated them into projects, driving innovation and staying ahead of the technology curve.

Led the AI department of Naardic AS (Norway's largest online interactive gym company), heading the tech development that resulted in a tech solution far more advanced than competitors. Some notable achievements include:

- Devising and executing the AI strategy to gamify fitness and workouts, culminating in the creation of an
 advanced video conferencing system with computer vision at its core. This system effectively replaced
 traditional solutions like Zoom, resulting in a 2X increase in customer acquisition and retention due to enhanced
 features and experiences.
- Pioneering the deep learning based repetition counter system and AR based rep-counter within the video conferencing system, using Mediapipe, blazepose, pose estimation and customer trainer DNN model trainer on

- **a large custom dataset**. This innovation introduced real-time competition among customers through leaderboards and real time Al generated feedback.
- Innovating one of the industry's first avatar systems to mimic customers' full-body movements in real time within the video conferencing system, offering personalization and customization options.
- Leading the development of a video processing unit designed to seamlessly record and enhance videos by
 overlaying customized text, image and critical information. This pioneering effort has resulted in the creation of a
 video library, significantly reducing the operational costs by replacing the real trainers with recorded classes.
- Leading the development of a recommendation system of fitness classes from the coming week schedule.
- Creating a 3D virtual companion that offers real-time conversational interactions. This project involved utilizing
 technologies such as Unity3D, RVC, Reallusion CC4, Langchain, and GPT etc. This intricate project incorporated
 voice cloning, 3D avatar animation, MongoDB, fine-tuning of LLM, prompt engineering etc.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - ML, CREATEBYTES, GURUGRAM, INDIA

2021 - 2021

As a Team Lead and Senior Software Engineer within the Research and Development Team, I played a pivotal role in overseeing concurrent product development efforts. My contributions encompassed:

- Pioneering the development of a **captcha prediction system** capable of automatically deciphering captchas.
- Architecting an advanced **anatomical part prediction model** specifically tailored for femur bone.
- Work an anthropometric parameter prediction system using the point cloud of a human body.

VISION ENGINEER, SUREWASH, DUBLIN, IRELAND

2019 - 2020

Leading the training, development, and deployment of Vision Systems for kiosk systems and mobile applications.

- Collaborating on a vision-based research project with professors from Trinity College and Enterprise Ireland.
- Utilizing Azure Kinect Camera for body tracking and pose estimation to create an MVP for a new product.
- Successfully completing multiple projects related to **object detection**, **classification**, **and segmentation** using DL approach (MobileNet SSD, MobileNet, Faster RCNN, YOLO, TensorFlow Lite etc.) and classical vision and machine learning techniques (feature extraction, SVM etc.)
- Proficiency in data collection, annotation, preprocessing, and augmentation of large image datasets.
- Experience in working with Intel RealSense Depth Cameras, depth values and classical computer vision.

SYSTEM ENGINEER, TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES, BENGALURU, INDIA

2015 - 2018

- As a Team Lead performed client interaction, quality check, code reviews, requirement and feasibility analysis.
- As a Senior Java developer having experience in the development and automation of large-scale applications.

EDUCATION

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE – INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS TRINITY COLLEGE DUBLIN, DUBLIN IRELAND

SEPTEMBER 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2019

Grade: First Class 69%

<u>Dissertation:</u> User Experience enhancement using three different forms of Augmented Reality namely **Marker-based AR, Marker-less AR, Object Detection-based AR,** implemented using AR Kit, Vuforia, and Unity3D.

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING - COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING SIR M VISVESVARAYA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, BENGALURU, INDIA

AUGUST 2011 – AUGUST 2015

Grade: First Class 67.02%

CERTIFICATIONS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Based on my performance, I was showcased on Agilis AS, Createbytes, Surewash company's website.
- Received "Start Team", "Best Team" and "On the Spot" award for distinguished performance.
- Completed Deep Learning Specialization, Generative AI Specialization etc. from Deepleaning.ai, Google etc.
- Achieved Grade B in Data Analytics and Data Mining Course under CCE program from India Institute of Science.